Month-end review often splits one decision
across a ledger, invoice,
policy, spreadsheet, and sign-off.
BalanceDocket gives controllers one
evidence-bound path through the exception,
keeping calculation, model advice,
and human authority separate.
This is a bundled synthetic June close.
Through the BalanceDocket skill,
Codex generates the fixture, runs the
local case, checks status, and prepares
the bounded advisory. The baseline needs
no model, network,
OpenAI account, or API key.
Inside Adjustments, the invoice period
runs from June fifteenth,
twenty twenty-six, through June
fourteenth, twenty twenty-seven.
Controls—not the model—verify its
identity and cutoff, then allocate
sixteen of three hundred sixty-five
days to June:
five thousand two hundred sixty kronor
and twenty-seven öre expense;
one hundred fourteen thousand seven
hundred thirty-nine kronor
and seventy-three öre prepaid.
This retained Codex run requested
GPT-5.6 Sol
through my eligible ChatGPT plan,
without an API key.
BalanceDocket sent bounded synthetic
excerpts, exact amounts,
and a strict schema. The result passed
schema, citation, amount,
no-authority, and snapshot checks.
Codex CLI did not report the returned
model, so I disclose the request
without claiming independent confirmation.
The result is labeled
“Codex requested, validated output.”
It selected three source-linked citations,
reported medium uncertainty,
and flagged missing evidence.
Provider prose was discarded.
BalanceDocket builds the conclusion
locally from validated selections
and fixed amounts. The advisory cannot
change calculations, approve, post,
lock, pay, file, send, or alter
source data.
Authority stays with the reviewer.
I record that the cited service period and
exact integer-öre allocation support
prepaid treatment, while missing
evidence needs follow-up.
I choose Request evidence—the safe,
repeatable disposition.
The decision stays bound to this snapshot
in an append-only local hash chain;
no ERP write occurs.
The workpaper binds source hashes,
deterministic calculation,
advisory hash, human rationale, action,
snapshot, chain head,
and validation scope. It reports
zero accounting actions
and zero ERP writes, so another reviewer
can audit the decision.
Codex accelerated the Python and React
build, tests,
accessibility, and release checks.
I made every product decision
and final judgment.